Register of the Roy A. Childs papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Roy A. Childs papers,
1933-1994
93053
Hoover Institution Archives
46 manuscript boxes (18.4 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, studies, memoranda, bulletins, serial issues, pamphlets, clippings, and sound recordings relating to libertarian thought and activities in the United States, laissez-faire economics, and proposals for decriminalization of drug use.
Childs, Roy A., 1949-1992.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1993.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Roy A. Childs was born on January 4th, 1949, in Buffalo, New York. He was a prominent lecturer, essayist, and critic, and is perhaps best known as a zealous libertarian thinker.
From a very young age, Childs became interested in the libertarian tradition. Before he entered high school he was already reading up on political issues and introducing himself to the classics of individualist thought. Childs graduated from high school in 1966, and shortly thereafter enrolled at the University of New York at Buffalo, with the goal of becoming a professor. Shortly after enrolling at Buffalo he became enthralled by the work of Robert LeFevre and as a result won a full scholarship to LeFevre's Comprehensive Course at his famous Freedom School, and thus left Buffalo in 1967. His education and intellectual thirst took him from Buffalo, to the Freedom School, and back to Buffalo by the fall of 1968, when the Freedom School buckled. The following year, he wrote his famous, “Open Letter to Ayn Rand,” thus quickly solidifying his place in the libertarian world.
During his career, Childs took on many roles. From 1977 to 1981 he was an editor of the Libertarian Review. Later, from 1982 to 1984, he was a scholar at the Cato Institute, a prominent libertarian think tank. Childs not only produced his own writings but he was also the editor and reviewer of hundreds of articles, books, and essays, many of which were created during his time with Laissez Faire Books.
Childs died on May 22, 1992, leaving behind a legacy and a lasting impact on the libertarian tradition.
Scope and Content
The collection documents the professional career of Roy A. Childs Jr. The collection is divided into three series: correspondence, printed matter, and speeches and writings. The first series documents the personal and professional correspondence sent and received by Childs between 1967 and 1992. The second series is composed of printed matter in the form of articles, book jackets, newspaper clippings, and various periodicals covering the time period of 1965 to 1992. Speeches and writings make up the third and last series of the collection, which documents the time period between 1933 and 1994. Materials in this series are composed of writings by various authors including the writings of Roy A. Childs as well as his research notes. Some of the subjects covered in the reaserach notes include: Cold War, defense, drug legalization, foreign policy, the Holocaust, land reform, libertarianism, Ayn Rand, and Young Americans for Freedom.
Related Collection(s)
Joan Kennedy Taylor papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Drug legalization.; Journalists.; Laissez-faire.; Libertarianism--United States.; Liberty.; United States--Politics and government.
- Correspondence File, 1967-1992
  Scope and Content
  Materials in this series are mainly composed of correspondence and letters between Roy A. Childs and his various associates and colleagues. The correspondence varies in nature from personal to professional.
  - Aldrige, Robert C., 1982 (Text : 1: 1)
  - Amrod, Jerry, 1969 (Text : 1: 2)
  - Anderson, Martin, 1988 (Text : 1: 3)
  - Anyaeche, Joseph, 1984 (Text : 1: 4)
  - Ardoyno, Jack, 1980 (Text : 1: 5)
  - Attarian, John, 1985 (Text : 1: 6)
  - Atterbury, Betsy, J., 1987 (Text : 1: 7)
  - Avery, Peter, 1971 (Text : 1: 8)
  - Bahr, Bill, 1980 (Text : 1: 9)
  - Ball, George, W., 1983 (Text : 1: 10)
  - Bandow, Doug, 1984-1988 (Text : 1: 11)
  - Barber, Chuck, 1986 (Text : 1: 12)
  - Barnet, Richard, 1977 (Text : 1: 13)
  - Bartley, Robert, 1982 (Text : 1: 14)
  - Bartucci, Richard, 1985 (Text : 1: 15)
  - Bauer, Peter, 1980-1981 (Text : 1: 16)
  - Bauman, Robert, circa 1980 (Text : 1: 17)
  - Beckmann, Petr, 1980 (Text : 1: 18)
  - Beckner, Steve, 1977 (Text : 1: 19)
  - Bell, Daniel, 1978 (Text : 1: 20)
  - Benko, Gregor, 1974 (Text : 1: 21)
  - Berry, Susan, (Letters from Roy), 1967-1970 (Text : 1: 22)
  - Berry, Susan, (Letters from Susan), 1968 (Text : 1: 23)
  - Birmingham, Bill, 1986 (Text : 1: 24)
  - Blackwell, Morton C., 1977 (Text : 1: 25)
  - Blake, Robert, 1980 (Text : 1: 26)
  - Bleiberg, Robert, 1976-1982 (Text : 1: 27)
  - Block, Walter, 1982-1992 (Text : 1: 28)
  - Blumenthal, Joan Mitchell, 1982-1983 (Text : 1: 29)
  - Blundell, John, 1992 (Text : 1: 30)
  - Boaz, David D., 1981 (Text : 1: 31)
  - Bock, Alan, 1977 (Text : 1: 32)
  - Bode, Edward C., 1979 (Text : 1: 33)
  - Boehme, Lillian R., 1970 (Text : 1: 34)
  - Boland, John C., 1982 (Text : 1: 35)
  - Bolick, Clint, 1988 (Text : 1: 36)
  - Branden, Nathaniel, 1969-1985 (Text : 1: 37)
  - Bray, Richard A., circa 1980 (Text : 1: 38)
  - Brittan, Samuel, 1979 (Text : 1: 39)
  - Brodrick, Susan, circa 1985 (Text : 1: 40)
  - Brooks, David, 1992 (Text : 1: 41)
  - Borther, John, 1991 (Text : 1: 42)
  - Brown, David M., 1982 (Text : 1: 43)
  - Brudnoy, David, circa 1980 (Text : 1: 44)
  - Bryan, Pat, 1987 (Text : 1: 45)
  - Buchanan, Patrick, 1983 (Text : 1: 46)
  - Campaigne, Jameson, Jr., 1992 (Text : 1: 47)
  - Cauchon, Dennis, 1985 (Text : 1: 48)
  - Chase, Bill, 1971 (Text : 1: 49)
  - Childs, Roy A., 1983 (Text : 1: 50)
  - Chitester, Robert J., 1989 (Text : 1: 51)
  - Clark, Ed, 1979-1983 (Text : 1: 52)
  - Clarke, Philip C., 1977 (Text : 1: 53)
  - Cocrbum, Alex, 1984 (Text : 1: 54)
  - Connor, Charles, H., 1977 (Text : 1: 55)
  - Cooke, Robert, 1978 (Text : 1: 56)
  - Cooley, Bruce, 1979-1981 (Text : 1: 57)
  - Cooper, Frank, 1978 (Text : 1: 58)
  - Coors, William K., 1980 (Text : 1: 59)
  - Crane, Edward, 1977-1991 (Text : 1: 60)
  - Dame, Tom, 1978 (Text : 2: 1)
  - Danks, Bill, 1969-1970 (Text : 2: 2)
  - Decter, Midge, 1987 (Text : 2: 3)
  - Dickerson, Catherine, 1986 (Text : 2: 4)
  - Donway, Roger, 1991 (Text : 2: 5)
  - Dorffi, Cristine, 1992 (Text : 2: 6)
  - Douglas, Jack D., 1991 (Text : 2: 7)
  - Downard, Jim, 1982 (Text : 2: 8)
  - Driver, Garston Wallace, Jr., 1980 (Text : 2: 9)
  - Ebeling, Richard M., 1987 (Text : 2: 10)
  - Eeingenburg, Brian, 1970 (Text : 2: 11)
  - Efron, Edith, 1977 (Text : 2: 12)
  - Eggleston, George T., 1980 (Text : 2: 13)
  - Emerling, Michael, 1978 (Text : 2: 14)
  - Epstein, Richard A., 1991 (Text : 2: 15)
  - Ernsberger, Don, circa 1980 (Text : 2: 16)
  - Evans, Bruce, 1991 (Text : 2: 17)
  - Ferguson, Tim, circa 1980 (Text : 2: 18)
  - Ferns, Harry, 1977 (Text : 2: 19)
  - Flood, Tony, 1987 (Text : 2: 20)
  - Folsom, Burt, 1988 (Text : 2: 21)
  - Frantz, Roger, 1989 (Text : 2: 22)
  - Friedlander, Lanny, 1969 (Text : 2: 23)
  - Friedman, David, 1969 (Text : 2: 24)
  - Friedman, Jeff, 1979-1986 (Text : 2: 25)
  - Friedman, Milton, 1974 (Text : 2: 26)
  - Gillis, John and Cynthia, 1990 (Text : 2: 27)
  - Glisson, Robert, 1988 (Text : 2: 28)
  - Gloria, 1978 (Text : 2: 29)
  - Goddard, Arthur, 1970 (Text : 2: 30)
  - Gofman, John W., 1982 (Text : 2: 31)
  - Gonze, Josh, 1992 (Text : 2: 32)
  - Gordon, Lawrence M., 1981 (Text : 2: 33)
  - Gottlieb, Sanford, 1979 (Text : 2: 34)
  - Greenberg, Gary, circa 1980 (Text : 2: 35)
  - Greenberg, Sidney, 1977 (Text : 2: 36)
  - Grinder, Walter E., 1969-1977 (Text : 2: 37)
  - Gundereson, Gerald, 1989 (Text : 2: 38)
  - Hagel, John, III, 1970 (Text : 2: 39)
  - Hammett, William, M. H., 1979-1990 (Text : 2: 40)
  - Hanseon, Peter J., 1982 (Text : 2: 41)
  - Hardesty, Michael, 1982-1987 (Text : 2: 42)
  - Harper, F. A., 1968-1970 (Text : 2: 43)
  - Harrington, Byron L., 1985 (Text : 2: 44)
  - Hart, David, 1986-1987 (Text : 2: 45)
  - Harvey, Steve, 1982 (Text : 2: 46)
  - Hawkins, Dale, 1977 (Text : 2: 47)
  - Hayden, Robert, 1970 (Text : 2: 48)
  - Hayek, Friedrich A., 1977 (Text : 2: 49)
  - Hazlitt, Henry, 1977-1979 (Text : 2: 50)
  - Henderson, David, 1990-1992 (Text : 2: 51)
  - Hess, Karl, circa 1980 (Text : 2: 52)
  - Hessen, Robert, 1972-1986 (Text : 2: 53)
  - Hind, Rick, 1979 (Text : 2: 54)
  - Hohenstein, Henry John, 1988 (Text : 2: 55)
  - Hospers, John, 1978-1983 (Text : 2: 56)
  - Hummel, Jeff, 1986-1989 (Text : 3: 1)
  - Jacobs, Eric and Rebecca, 1968 (Text : 3: 2)
  - Jeck, James, 1969 (Text : 3: 3)
  - Joffe, Marc, 1982 (Text : 3: 4)
  - Johnson, Paul M., 1982 (Text : 3: 5)
  - Jordan, Les, 1969 (Text : 3: 6)
  - Kapp, Richard P., 1978 (Text : 3: 7)
  - Kauffman, Bill, 1987 (Text : 3: 8)
  - Kelso, Robert P., 1983 (Text : 3: 9)
  - Kennan, George F., 1978 (Text : 3: 10)
  - Kephart, Robert D., 1970-1988 (Text : 3: 11)
  - Kerr, Robert W., 1979 (Text : 3: 12)
  - Kilpatrick, James Jackson, 1978 (Text : 3: 13)
  - Kinsley, Michael, 1988 (Text : 3: 14)
  - Kirzner, Israel, 1977 (Text : 3: 15)
  - Klare, Michael, 1977 (Text : 3: 16)
  - Klein, Dan, 1991 (Text : 3: 17)
  - Konkin, Samuel Edward, III, 1981-1988 (Text : 3: 18)
  - Kristol, Irving, 1979 (Text : 3: 19)
  - Kroy, Moshe, 1977 (Text : 3: 20)
  - Kurtz, Paul, 1989 (Text : 3: 21)
  - La Conca, Riccardo, 1977 (Text : 3: 22)
  - La Rocque, Eugene, 1982 (Text : 3: 23)
  - Lavoie, Don, 1978 (Text : 3: 24)
  - LeFevre, Robert, and Rampart College, 1967-1985 (Text : 3: 25)
  - Lewis, Flora, 1982 (Text : 3: 26)
  - Liggio, Leonard, 1978 (Text : 3: 27)
  - Lindbergh, Kristina R., 1983 (Text : 3: 28)
  - Ludlow, Lawrence M., 1988 (Text : 3: 29)
  - Lynch, Fredrick, 1989-1990 (Text : 3: 30)
  - MacBride, Roger Lea, 1983 (Text : 3: 31)
  - Macedo, Stephen, 1987 (Text : 3: 32)
  - Machan, Tibor, 1970-1987 (Text : 3: 33)
  - Mack, Eric, 1979 (Text : 3: 34)
  - Maiorana, Joseph, 1969 (Text : 3: 35)
  - Majors, Powell, 1989 (Text : 3: 36)
  - Marina, William, 1977 (Text : 3: 37)
  - Martin, James J., 1970-1972 (Text : 3: 38)
  - McMaffrey, Neil, 1967 (Text : 3: 39)
  - McCarty, John T., 1977 (Text : 3: 40)
  - Meadows, Edward, 1979 (Text : 3: 41)
  - Meiers, Robert L., 1969 (Text : 3: 42)
  - Mellor III, William H., 1990 (Text : 3: 43)
  - Mill, John Stuart, 1988 (Text : 3: 44)
  - Miller, Geoff, 1982 (Text : 3: 45)
  - von Mises, Margit, 1978 (Text : 3: 46)
  - Mollison, Susan F., 1977 (Text : 3: 47)
  - Morley, Felix, 1973 (Text : 3: 48)
  - Moro, Lisa, 1991 (Text : 3: 49)
  - Mueller, Milton, 1982 (Text : 3: 50)
  - Nash, Edward, 1969-1970 (Text : 3: 51)
  - Nash, Ronald, 1987 (Text : 3: 52)
  - Navasky, Victor, 1978 (Text : 3: 53)
  - Nelson, John O., 1968 (Text : 3: 54)
  - Newman, Patty, 1977 (Text : 3: 55)
  - Nisbet, Robert, 1977 (Text : 3: 56)
  - Nozick, Robert, 1977 (Text : 3: 57)
  - Nymeyer, Fredrick, 1977 (Text : 3: 58)
  - O'Connor, Frank, Mrs., 1978 (Text : 3: 59)
  - O'Connor, Max, 1989 (Text : 3: 60)
  - O'Driscoll, Gerald P., 1977 (Text : 3: 61)
  - Osdoby, Sima R., 1982 (Text : 3: 62)
  - Padden, David H., 1977 (Text : 3: 63)
  - Palmer, Tom G., 1988 (Text : 4: 1)
  - Paul, Jeffrey, 1991 (Text : 4: 2)
  - Paul, Ron, 1982 (Text : 4: 3)
  - Pearson, George, 1969-1982 (Text : 4: 4)
  - Peden, Joe, 1969 (Text : 4: 5)
  - Peikoff, Leonard, 1969-1972 (Text : 4: 6)
  - Pettingill, John, 1968 (Text : 4: 7)
  - Phillips, Howard, 1977 (Text : 4: 8)
  - Phillips, Kevin P., 1977 (Text : 4: 9)
  - Pippin, Steven, 1992 (Text : 4: 10)
  - Plekhanov, Sergey, 1979 (Text : 4: 11)
  - Podhoretz, Norman, 1983 (Text : 4: 12)
  - Poole, Robert, Jr., 1969-1982 (Text : 4: 13)
  - Price, Melanie, 1988 (Text : 4: 14)
  - Raimondo, Justin, 1990 (Text : 4: 15)
  - Ravenal, Earl, 1986 (Text : 4: 16)
  - Read, Leonard E., 1981 (Text : 4: 17)
  - Reason, 1978-1980 (Text : 4: 18)
  - Reed, Adam W., 1979 (Text : 4: 19)
  - Rhodes, John, 1982 (Text : 4: 20)
  - Rich, Howard, 1986 (Text : 4: 21)
  - Richman, Sheldon L., 1989-1991 (Text : 4: 22)
  - Rohfling, Fritz, 1977 (Text : 4: 23)
  - Rollins, Louis, 1969 (Text : 4: 24)
  - Rothbard, Murray N., 1977 (Text : 4: 25)
  - Ryavec, Karl W., 1983 (Text : 4: 26)
  - Schonberg, Harold C., 1982 (Text : 4: 27)
  - Schulman, Lee and Joyce, 1979 (Text : 4: 28)
  - Schwartz, Mordecai, 1982 (Text : 4: 29)
  - Schwartz, Peter, 1969-1982 (Text : 4: 30)
  - Schwartzman, Jack, 1987 (Text : 4: 31)
  - Sciabarra, Chris M., 1988-1989 (Text : 4: 32)
  - Sherrill, Bob, 1970 (Text : 4: 33)
  - Silverman, Henry J., 1969 (Text : 4: 34)
  - Simon, Julian, L., 1990 (Text : 4: 35)
  - Slocum, Gordon, 1983 (Text : 4: 36)
  - Smith, Dalton, 1969 (Text : 4: 37)
  - Smith, George, 1978 (Text : 4: 38)
  - Smith, Kay Nolte, 1980-1983 (Text : 4: 39)
  - Smith, Reid, 1980 (Text : 4: 40)
  - Stanford, Phil, circa 1980 (Text : 4: 41)
  - Steinberg, Arnold, 1979 (Text : 4: 42)
  - Sterling, Eric E., 1987 (Text : 4: 43)
  - Stiver, Bill, circa 1980 (Text : 4: 44)
  - Stromberg, Josef, 1977 (Text : 4: 45)
  - Strossen, Nadine, 1991 (Text : 4: 46)
  - Summers, Brian, 1991 (Text : 4: 47)
  - Szasz, Thomas, 1986 (Text : 4: 48)
  - Tannehill, Morris and Linda, 1969-1985 (Text : 4: 49)
  - Taylor, Joan Kennedy, 1978, 1984 (Text : 4: 50)
  - Theroux, David J., 1977 (Text : 4: 51)
  - Thornton, Mark, 1991 (Text : 4: 52)
  - Timko, Michael, 1980 (Text : 4: 53)
  - Traband, Roy, 1977 (Text : 4: 54)
  - Veatch, Henry B., 1972 (Text : 4: 55)
  - Villa, Joseph, 1982 (Text : 4: 56)
  - Voigt, Stephen B., 1992 (Text : 4: 57)
  - Warner, Stuart D., circa 1980 (Text : 4: 58)
  - Watner, Carl, 1987-1988 (Text : 4: 59)
  - Weber, Christopher, circa 1977 (Text : 4: 60)
  - Wheeler, Jack, 1969 (Text : 4: 61)
  - Wieder, Charles G., 1979 (Text : 5: 1)
  - Wiener, Daniel, 1979 (Text : 5: 2)
  - Wilcke, Richard W., 1978 (Text : 5: 3)
  - Williamson, Chilton, Jr., 1978 (Text : 5: 4)
  - Winter, Thomas S., 1980 (Text : 5: 5)
  - Wollstein, Jarret, 1968-1970 (Text : 5: 6)
  - Wood, John B., 1978 (Text : 5: 7)
  - Wortham, Anne, 1988 (Text : 5: 8)
  - Yergin, Daniel, 1977 (Text : 5: 9)
  - Unidentified, 1970-1991 (Text : 5: 10)
- Printed Matter, 1965-1992
  Comprised of articles, book jackets, newspaper clippings, pamphlets and various periodicals.
  - Articles, 1977-1992 (Text : 5: 11-12)
  - Book jackets, circa 1980 (Text : 5: 13)
  - Clippings, 1986-1992 (Text : 5: 14-15)
  - Clippings, 1986-1992 (Text : 6: 1-2)
  - Pamphlets, 1967-1987 (Text : 6: 3)
  - Periodicals, 1965-1992
    Periodicals are organized in alphabetical order and include periodicals to which Roy A. Childs subscribed as well as periodicals he wrote for and collected.
    - The Abolitionist, 1970 (Text : 6: 4)
    - Account, 1990-1992 (Text : 6: 5)
    - Aristos: The Journal of Esthetics, 1987-1991 (Text : 6: 6)
    - Austrian Economics Newsletter, 1991 (Text : 6: 7)
    - Books for Libertarians, circa 1970 (Text : 6: 8)
    - Capitalism and Freedom, 1982 (Text : 6: 9)
    - Cato Policy Report, 1988-1992 (Text : 6: 10)
    - Chronicles, 1990 (Text : 6: 11)
    - The City Journal, 1992 (Text : 6: 12)
    - Conservative Book Club Bulletin, circa 1980 (Text : 6: 13)
    - Counter Point, circa 1980 (Text : 6: 14)
    - Cryonics, 1989-1992 (Text : 6: 15)
    - The Dandelion, 1977-1978 (Text : 6: 16)
    - Dissent, circa 1980 (Text : 6: 17)
    - Econ'87, 1987 (Text : 6: 18)
    - Econ Update, 1989 (Text : 7: 1)
    - The Entrepreneur, 1987 (Text : 7: 2)
    - Focus, 1969-1971 (Text : 7: 3)
    - Forum News, 1987 (Text : 7: 4)
    - The Foundation for Economic Education, 1977-1989 (Text : 7: 5)
    - Fragments, 1965-1980 (Text : 7: 6)
    - Free Inquiry, 1989 (Text : 7: 7)
    - The Free Market, 1991 (Text : 7: 8)
    - Freedom Network News, 1991 (Text : 7: 9)
    - Freedom's Child, 1981 (Text : 7: 10)
    - Georgia Law Review, 1979 (Text : 7: 11)
    - Heterodoxy, 1992 (Text : 7: 12)
    - Imprimis, 1992 (Text : 7: 13)
    - In Practice, 1990 (Text : 7: 14)
    - The Independent, circa 1990 (Text : 7: 15)
    - Individual Liberty, 1987 (Text : 7: 16)
    - Inform, 1978-1980 (Text : 7: 17)
    - Institute for Historical Review, 1991 (Text : 7: 18)
    - Institute Scholar, 1981-1989 (Text : 7: 19)
    - The International Journal of Research and Progress in Management Economics, 1988 (Text : 7: 20)
    - Intervention, circa 1970 (Text : 7: 21)
    - Invictus, 1969-1975 (Text : 7: 22)
    - ISI Campus Report, circa 1970 (Text : 8: 1)
    - Issues and Views, 1986 (Text : 8: 2)
    - Journal of Polymorphous Perversity, 1986 (Text : 8: 3)
    - Law and Liberty, 1975-1980 (Text : 8: 4)
    - LeFevre's Journal, 1973-1976 (Text : 8: 5)
    - Liberalia, circa 1990 (Text : 8: 6)
    - The Libertarian, 1987 (Text : 8: 7)
    - Libertarian Agenda, 1988 (Text : 8: 8)
    - Libertarian Alliance, circa 1991 (Text : 8: 9)
    - Libertarian American, 1967-1969 (Text : 8: 10)
    - Libertarian Connection, circa 1969 (Text : 8: 11)
    - Libertarian Familist, 1990-1992 (Text : 8: 12)
    - The Libertarian Forum, 1984 (Text : 8: 13)
    - Libertarians for Gay and Lesbian Concerns Newsletter, 1985-1986 (Text : 8: 14)
    - Libertarian Party News, 1982 (Text : 8: 15)
    - Libertarian Republican, 1990 (Text : 8: 16)
    - Liberty and Society, 1992 (Text : 8: 17)
    - Man and State: A Journal of Individualist Thought, 1968 (Text : 8: 18)
    - Market Process, 1990 (Text : 8: 19)
    - Michigan Libertarian, 1988 (Text : 8: 20)
    - New Capitalist, 1970 (Text : 8: 21)
    - New Libertarian, 1987 (Text : 8: 22)
    - Newsletter of the Ayn Rand Institute, 1987-1989 (Text : 8: 23)
    - Nomos: Studies in Spontaneous Order, 1987 (Text : 8: 24)
    - Oasis, 1987 (Text : 8: 25)
    - The Objectivist Newsletter, 1965 (Text : 9: 1)
    - Oregon Libertarian, 1987 (Text : 9: 2)
    - Outlook, 1980 (Text : 9: 3)
    - Palo Alto Book Service, 1985 (Text : 9: 4)
    - Pine Tree, 1970 (Text : 9: 5)
    - The Pragmatist, 1988 (Text : 9: 6)
    - Praxis, 1991 (Text : 9: 7)
    - Public Opinion, 1980 (Text : 9: 8)
    - Rally, 1967 (Text : 9: 10)
    - Rampart College, Freedom School Bulletin, 1965-1966 (Text : 9: 11)
    - Rampart College Newsletter, 1966-1968 (Text : 9: 12)
    - Rampart Institute: Prospectus and Annual Report, 1980 (Text : 9: 13)
    - Rapport, 1970 (Text : 9: 14)
    - Reason, 1968-1969 (Text : 9: 15)
    - Reason Report, 1987 (Text : 9: 16)
    - Safetynet, 1992 (Text : 9: 17)
    - Second Renaissance Books, 1991-1992 (Text : 9: 18)
    - Sil Services Bulletin, 1970 (Text : 9: 19)
    - The Skeptical Inquirer, 1989 (Text : 9: 20)
    - Toward Liberty, 1981 (Text : 9: 21)
    - Update, 1982-1984 (Text : 9: 22)
    - The Voluntaryist, 1986-1987 (Text : 9: 23)
- Speeches and Writings, 1933-1994
  Materials in speeches and writings are composed of research notes and writings of Roy A. Childs. Additionally, this series includes writings by various authors.
  - Research Notes, 1933-1992
    Comprised of various research topics Child wrote about or in which he had interest. The research notes cover a number of different topics, some of which include: Cold War, conservatives, defense, drug legalization, foreign policy, the Holocaust, Israeli land policy, land reform, liberals and the libertarian party, objectivism, Ayn Rand, and Young Americans for Freedom. Additionally, the research notes include materials dedicated to the Institute for Humane Studies.
    - "The Alternative of Liberty,", 1970-1977 (Text : 10: 1)
    - Articles recommended by associates of Roy A. Childs, 1970-1992 (Text : 10: 2-3)
    - Block, Walter, circa 1980 (Text : 10: 4)
    - Catalog IQ, circa 1986 (Text : 10: 5)
    - Cato Institute, circa 1980 (Text : 10: 6)
    - Cato Institute, circa 1980 (Text : 11: 1-4)
    - Cato Institute - Dartmouth, Summer Seminar, "The Ethics of Liberty,", 1983 (Text : 11: 5)
    - Cato Institute - Stanford, Summer Seminar, "The Ethics of Liberty,", 1978 (Text : 11: 6-7)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes compact sound cassette tape.
    - Cato Institute - Dartmouth, Summer Seminar, "The Future of Liberty,", 1983 (Text : 12: 1)
    - Cato Institute - Dartmouth, Summer Seminar, "The History of the Modern Libertarian Movement,", 1983 (Text : 12: 2)
    - Cato Institute - Dartmouth, Summer Seminar, "Liberty and the Third World,", 1983 (Text : 12: 3)
    - Cockburn, Alexander, 1979-1980 (Text : 12: 4)
    - Cold War, circa 1980 (Text : 12: 5)
    - Conservatives, 1978-1981 (Text : 12: 6)
    - Critical Review, 1978-1988 (Text : 12: 7)
    - Defense, 1977-1980 (Text : 13: 1)
    - Drug Legalization, 1980-1982 (Text : 13: 2)
    - Drug Legalization, 1984-1986 (Text : 13: 3)
    - Drug Legalization, circa 1980 (Text : 13: 4)
    - Drug Legalization, 1986 (Text : 13: 5)
    - Drug Legalization, 1987 (Text : 13: 6)
    - Drug Legalization, 1989 (Text : 13: 7)
    - Drug Legalization, 1990 (Text : 13: 8-10)
    - Drug Legalization (Thomas Szasz manuscript), circa 1990 (Text : 13: 11)
    - Drug Legalization (Thomas Szasz manuscript), circa 1990 (Text : 14: 1-3)
    - Drug Legalization, 1991 (Text : 14: 4-6)
    - Drug Legalization, 1991 (Text : 15: 1)
    - Drug Legalization, 1988-1991 (Text : 15: 2-3)
    - Drug Legalization, 1989-1991 (Text : 15: 4-5)
    - El Salvador, 1981 (Text : 16: 1)
    - Foregin Policy, 1981 (Text : 16: 2)
    - Holocaust, 1992 (Text : 16: 3)
    - Hubert, Peter, 1988 (Text : 16: 4)
    - Institute for Humane Studies, 1988-1991
      General information on the Institute for Humane Studies. Additionally, includes files on the Felix Morley writing contest participants. Roy A. Childs was one of the judges for the contest and the files he collected provide examples of essays that were submitted for consideration.
      - Felix Morley Prize - Boettke, Peter J., 1988 (Text : 16: 5)
      - Felix Morley Prize - Frederick, Brian, 1988 (Text : 16: 6)
      - Felix Morley Prize - King, Gerlad, 1988 (Text : 16: 7)
      - Felix Morley Prize - Lowry, Ray W., 1988 (Text : 16: 8)
      - Felix Morley Prize - Shelor, R. Edward., 1988 (Text : 16: 9)
      - Felix Morley Prize - Taylor, Jeffrey, 1988 (Text : 16: 10)
      - Felix Morley Prize - Vaksman, Fabian, 1988 (Text : 16: 11)
      - General, circa 1990 (Text : 16: 12)
      - Memos, 1991 (Text : 16: 13)
    - Israeli Land Policy, circa 1980 (Text : 16: 14)
    - Labadie, L., circa 1980 (Text : 16: 15)
    - Laissez-Faire-Books, circa 1990 (Text : 16: 16)
    - Land Reform, 1981 (Text : 16: 17)
    - Lane, Rose Wilder, 1933-1977 (Text : 17: 1)
    - LeFevre, 1969-1975 (Text : 17: 2)
    - Left, 1979-1980 (Text : 17: 3)
    - Liberals, circa 1980 (Text : 17: 4)
    - Libertarian Party, 1979-1982 (Text : 17: 5)
    - Libertarian Review, 1975-1978 (Text : 17: 6)
    - Libertarian Review Memos, 1972-1981 (Text : 17: 7)
    - Libertarians, circa 1985 (Text : 17: 8)
    - Neoconservatives, circa 1975 (Text : 18: 1)
    - New Republic, 1985 (Text : 18: 2)
    - North Atlantic Treaty Organization, 1979-1981 (Text : 18: 3-4)
    - Nozick, Robert, circa 1975 (Text : 18: 5)
    - Nyiregyhazi, Ervin, circa 1978 (Text : 19: 1-3)